Guide to the Heller House records, 1935-1999
Heller House records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Heller House records, 1935-1999
15-4-1886
Heller House (Ithaca, N.Y.).
0.5 cubic feet.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Research files of Elizabeth Hancock Sillin include "A Master Plan for the Miller-Heller House, 122 Eddy St., Ithaca, New York"; poem about William Henry Miller, 1906; letter about 1849 Chickering piano, 1944; "Life of John West Jackson," 1943; and letters to graduate students about history of Heller House. Also, correspondence and notes from or about Lillian Purvis Heller, 1940-1977. Also includes a stained glass fragment, videocassettes, slides, an audiocassette, photographs, and assorted papers.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
William Henry Miller was an architect in Ithaca, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Research files of Elizabeth Hancock Sillin include "A Master Plan for the Miller-Heller House, 122 Eddy St., Ithaca, New York"; poem about William Henry Miller, 1906; letter about 1849 Chickering piano, 1944; "Life of John West Jackson," 1943; and letters to graduate students about history of Heller House. Also, correspondence and notes from or about Lillian Purvis Heller, 1940-1977. Also includes a stained glass fragment, videocassettes, slides, an audiocassette, photographs, and assorted papers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Heller House (Ithaca, N.Y.).; Miller, William Henry, 1848-1922.; Sillin, Elizabeth Hancock.; Heller, Lillian Purvis.; Heller, Lillian Purvis; Miller, William Henry, 1848-1922; Sillin, Elizabeth Hancock
Subjects:
Architecture, Domestic -- Ithaca.; Architecture -- Ithaca.; Architecture; Architecture, Domestic; Dwellings
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.) -- Dwellings.; New York (State) -- Ithaca
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also: William Henry Miller miscellany, #2811
See also: William Henry Miller papers, #1856
SERIES LIST
Series I. Heller House Materials
Series II. Media
CONTAINER LIST
- Heller House Materials, 1935-1999
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Stained glass piece, Undated (Box 2)
  - Fabric piece, Undated (Box 1)
  - Hugh Troy Heller House photographs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Heller House tour tape notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence about Lillian Heller and Heller House, 1935-1938, 1947, 1957, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Includes photographs.
  - Life of John West Jackson, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Chickering piano letter, 1944-07-25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Copies of correspondence from or about Lillian Heller, 1947, 1957, 1960-1964, 1977, 1979, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Heller House slides, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Lillian Heller correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Early Heller House information inquiry, 1977-02-1977-04 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Heller House Project Questionnaire, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Copy of Lillian Heller's address book, 1980-07-11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Heller House slides, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Assorted photographs, 1988-11, 1991-06 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Heller House caretaker photographs, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miller reception materials, 1991-05 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Anders Zorn etching transfer to Johnson museum, 1992-06-1992-07 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Heller House financial information, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Photograph and slide notes, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Assorted photographs, Date Unknown (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Media, 1938-1998
  - Architecture Heller House, Undated; V-10681 (Box 1)
  - Heller House, Undated; V-10682 (Box 1)
  - Ed and Ginny Miller wedding, Undated; V-10683 (Box 1)
  - Mayo E. Roe on Heller House, 1938-1942; TR-17116 (Box 1)
  - Make a Difference Day, 1997-10-25; TR-17115 (Box 1)
  - Informal lecture/demonstration of pipe organ at Miller Heller House, 1998-05-14; V-10684 (Box 1)